Ah...
啊…
Oh no... It hurts...
惨了… 好痛…
Sorry... Suo-sama...
对不起…苏澳小哥哥…
I failed.
我失败了
Oh, I wish I could have patted you more...
啊… 还想多摸摸你呢
Lykos, stop!
黎可斯 不要！
Don't shoot!
别开枪！
Ho, aren't you the sister of Orca-sama?
噢 这不是奥尔卡司令的妹妹吗
Translator
翻
ssnake
译
静寂よ　旋律よ　儚き印よ
ssnake
Silence and melody, and the transient lives of Shirushi
静寂よ　旋律よ　儚き印よ
Timing
时 间 轴
zwc1991
zwc1991
砂上にこの地に　生き続けたのなら
砂上にこの地に　生き続けたのなら
If you have been living on the land, on the sea of sand
如果是在这沙海之上  生活下去
罪を纏う世界から　鯨の歌を聴いた...
罪を纏う世界から　鯨の歌を聴いた…
In a sinned world, we have heard the whale's lied
在罪业重重的世界里  我们曾侧耳倾听鲸鱼的歌唱…
運命を　感情を　抱くべき子たちよ
運命を　感情を　抱くべき子たちよ
Our fate and our emotions, my beloved children
不论命运  还是感情  亲爱的孩子们哟
さ  き
さ  き
その先へ　その未来へ
その先へ　その未来へ
Towards the future, go ahead
向着未来  向着前方
導かれたのなら
導かれたのなら
If you can be our guide
只要有你指引前路
幾千の声　空想の地へ
幾千の声　空想の地へ
Thousands of words, leaving for the fantasy lands
万千寄语  向着空想的彼岸
舵を切って行こうとした
舵を切って行こうとした
Steering towards the opposite
相信信念调转方向
バラード
バラード
幾千の声　砂の海の譚歌
幾千の声　砂の海の譚歌
Thousands of songs, they are the ballads of the sea of sand
万千欢声  是沙海的歌谣
F
雪 飘 工 作 室
L
雪 飘 工 作 室
So this must be my brother's idea.
这是哥哥算计的吧
It is a rule that we shouldn't kill anyone in the Room of Nous.
按说在「魂形之室」是不可以杀生的
He is the only one I know
毫不害怕触犯禁忌
who don't afraid about taboos.
这只有他做得出来
Give it up.
放弃吧
There's nothing you can do in this situation.
这个状态下你什么都做不到了
Why you insist on rebellion against us?
到头来你还是要反抗我们么
sentikinesis
thymia
Now you're only a child without thymia.
就凭你这一个连情念力都使不了的小孩么
So I've got no choice.
没办法
Don't move!
不许动
Put down your weapons, all of you!
旁边的也给我把武器扔了
If you dare to do anything, I'll cut off his head!
谁敢轻举妄动 我就切下这家伙的脑袋
Lykos!
黎可斯！
Lykos.
黎可斯
Tokusa... And my mates...
托库萨… 大家
Chakuro!
查克罗！
Go kill the Nous now!
快去把魂形干掉！
Oni...
欧尼…
Calm down.
冷静
To save the mud whale,
要拯救泥鲸
I have to think about the most important thing.
这是现在我最该考虑的事情
Lykos, let's go!
黎可斯 我们去！
The Nous is inside the room...
魂形就在 这里面…
What's that?
怎么回事
There's somebody there...
有谁在？
Oni!
欧尼！
Hey, Nibi-kko, Shaggy!
喂 尼比仔 蓬蓬头
What's the situation?
怎么样了！
I dunno! And stop call me Shaggy!
鬼知道！ 而且不许叫我蓬蓬头！
How can there be a raid right now!
这个时候突然袭击
Shit, we must be duped!
可恶 中计了么
We have no way out,
不管那么多了
but we three have to defend to the last.
这里就由我们三个死守
Right, Nibik...ko?
是吧 尼比…仔？
ひから
ひから
あなたが干涸び
あなたが干涸び
One day you will dry out.
你终将干涸
ひから
ひから
あなたが干涸び
あなたが干涸び
One day you will dry out.
你终将干涸
ひつぎ
ひつぎ
柩にその身を結わえられ
柩にその身を結わえられ
Your body will be tied inside a coffin.
你的身体终会系身灵柩
結わえられ
結わえられ
inside a coffin.
系身灵柩
いにしえ
いにしえ
古の深海の中
古の深海の中
Deep in the antique ocean,
在这悠久的深海之中
こぼ
こぼ
毀れども禁忌の園に
毀れども禁忌の園に
in the garden of ruins and sins,
在这坏灭而又禁忌的乐园里
園に
園に
ruins and sins,
乐园里
たっと
たっと
尊く生きん
尊く生きん
you continue to live with dignity.
尊贵地活下去
砂上の友よ
砂上の友よ
My friend on the sand
沙海上的朋友啊
愛しき友よ
愛しき友よ
My dear friend
我亲爱的朋友啊
Ah.
啊…
砂上の友よ
砂上の友よ
My friend on the sand
沙海上的朋友啊
Mom, there are hands!
妈妈 这儿长出手手来了
砂上の友よ
砂上の友よ
My friend on the sand
沙海上的朋友啊
What?
诶？
愛しき友よ
愛しき友よ
My dear friend
我亲爱的朋友啊
What's this?
…这是？
They are coming out!
咕噜咕噜地长出来了呢
And they are warm!
好暖和
愛しき友よ
愛しき友よ
My dear friend
我亲爱的朋友啊
There seems to be nobody in the farm and the residential area.
农园和居住区里 应该没有人
The counterattacks from the residents are all from nearby the 4 towers.
居民的攻击都是来自四个塔的周围
We're getting to know where our targets are.
逐渐把握住目标的所在了
Kill anyone as soon as you find.
发现一个杀掉一个
Because our mission is
因为我们的任务
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
"execution of all the sinners of the whale"
是「对全体鲸的罪人执行死刑」
By the way, where's the lion guy in your team?
对了 你们队里的狮子头去哪了
Do you mean Ryotari?
柳达理么
He is... eh...
那家伙…他…
So he is acting himself without permission again.
又擅自行动了么
I'll also make you cry!
让你也给我哭出来
Eyepatch!
眼罩！
Captain!
团长…
Suo...sama...?
苏澳…哥哥…？
What a terrible injury...
伤得好重…
What is it?
这是什么
What these fingers are?
这像手指一样的东西
They are as warm as the vital warmth...
好似体温般的温暖
As if... the mud whale is alive...
仿佛泥鲸…活着一样
Neri?
奈莉？
Something is...
有什么…
Entering... my head...
进入…我的脑海…
Something is... entering my head...
有什么…进入我的脑海…
That kid?
那个小朋友？
That kid.
那个小朋友
It's that kid.
就是那个小朋友
It's that kid, right?
就是那个小朋友呢
That kid.
那个小朋友
Is him that kid?
那个小朋友么？
Noooo!
不要！
I've been told that he jumped off the window in the school.
听说是从学校的窗子里跳出去的
Weird behavior again.
又是异常行为
Such a brother is our shame.
这样的弟弟真丢我们家的脸
We should lock him at home, never let him out.
把他关在家里不让他出去就好了
It's an illness.
这是病
His emotions are in disorder and out of control.
感情混乱 失去控制了
σάρξ
σάρξ
He had never eaten the sárx.
他又没吃过「魂肉」
But he is the only one whose emotions are not taken by the Nous.
魂形却不肯食用他的感情
The Nous didn't eat even a single piece of his emotions.
只有他的感情被全部留下来了
If there's a reason,
要说原因
it must be that strange thing happened
νοῦς
He kept telling us that something is flowing backwards.
他一直在说「发生逆流了」
What had flowed backwards to you, Ryotari?
柳达理 什么逆流了？
Mom, there were a lot of hearts!
妈妈 有好多好多 有好多好多心灵
Everybody should be...
本来啊 大家…
Ryotari, it's enough.
柳达理 够了
Inside the heart of a human being,
本来 人类的心灵里
there should be a large flower garden.
满满的都是花园
There are dirty slops... and big fires...
有脏兮兮的泥巴水…和热辣辣的大火灾
It's totally a mess!
是一团乱的！
It should be a mess!
明明本来是一团乱的
It's boring if you... hide it and act like a doll!
却要掩饰起来 打扮成傀儡娃娃
But, even if you guys here
不过 这里的家伙
are hated by the world and likely to die soon,
明明为世界所仇恨 马上就要去死了
you guys are living vivid!
却是这么生气勃勃！
I love you so much!
最喜欢你们了！
I have... seen your heart just now.
刚才 我看到了你的内心
If you feel sorrow...
要是你是这么悲伤…
If your world is tough...
要是你的世界是那么痛苦…
then why don't you live with us?
不如跟我们一起活下去吧
Even you...
就算你…
here
这里
can live in the mud whale just like Lykos...
也能像黎可斯那样 在泥鲸上…
That's impossible, our chief.
这可不行♪　首长先生
If everybody was like that girl,
要是大家都跟那个少女一样
we are not having such a war.
这样的战争根本就不会发生
How can you believe that we can make friend with someone who killed our fellows?
难不成你觉得事到如今 还能跟杀害过我们同胞的人交朋友么
Fallaina is buzzing.
法莱那已经开始喧嚣起来了
It seems that the borders are fluctuating.
彼此的界限恐怕已是岌岌可危
φάλαινα
νοῦς
νοῦς
这就是魂形·法莱那的力量么
Peeking at my heart without my permission...
随随便便就窥视别人
But don't mistake me!
别搞错了
Nobody has said I want to live with you guys!
谁说要跟你们活下去了
Don't you want to kill those who with vivid eyes?
老子就想搞死你们这些眼睛里有生气的家伙
I'd like to mess up those who acting like a human!
活得像个人类的家伙
That's a lot of fun, isn't it!
这才更有趣不是么
You idiot!
白痴！
I'm glad you have some fun.
你倒好 还有乐趣
For me, I even bother to live!
我啊 连活着都觉得麻烦
But according to what you mentioned,
不过 要如你所说的话
if I do this,
就算是我
even somebody like me can feel like
只要这样做就能感受到
I'm living!
活着的感觉！
No!
…不要～
I don't wanna die...
我不想…死
No.
不要
No, no...
不要 不要
Noooo!
不要啊！
No...
不…
Nooo...
不要…
Don't chase him!
别追了！
Why?
嗯？
He should be unable to do anything.
恐怕他 已经再做不了什么了
Rather than kill an enemy, I would like you
比起给予敌人致命一击
to think more about how to help our fellows.
我希望你能多考虑考虑怎么去帮助更多的伙伴
Please.
拜托你了
If you don't wanna die, then you just live.
你想活的话就活下去吧
Mr. Bobbed hair, I envy you that you want to live.
好羡慕你…能有想活下去的想法 娃娃头
No... No... No...
不要 不要 不要
No... No...
不要… 不要…
I don't want to die now.
我还 不想死
I want to live.
我要活下去
There are a lot of fun in my life.
还有好多有意思的事情
I am going to execute these guys.
我要把这些家伙全都处死
I am going to make them cry.
让他们哭泣
I want their reactions to me.
让他们对我有反应
In the heaven I finally found,
好不容易才找到的我的乐园
I want to play more with the guys on the Fallaina, forever.
还想永远永远 跟法莱那的家伙们玩耍下去
Enemy!
发现敌人了
He is full of blood. How scary he is!
他浑身是血 好可怕
Don't worry, we are going to kill him.
没关系 我们干掉他
But...
可是…
I said don't worry!
都说了没关系了
Scare...
尽管…
Scare of me more!
尽管害怕我吧
Come...
快点
and play with me, kids!
哥哥会好好陪你们玩的
What?
诶？
We hit him!
射中了！
There are... a lot of flowers...
有好多好多花…
Inside my mind... A lot...
在我心中…好多好多…
There are a lot of useless hears.
有好多好多无可救药的心灵
The world is out of joint.
这个世界太疯狂了
And nobody can understand me.
又有谁 能够理解我
Nah, Kicha.
呐 绮茶
Isn't it better if we were with our team at the base?
咱们留在我们班的据点那里比较好吧
How can we deal with the enemies if they come?
要是敌人来了 我们两个怎么办
Humph.
哼
Who knows whether the members of the team are still living or not.
咱们班那些人 现在怕是都不知道是死是活
It's the same wherever we are.
在哪都一样
And what about the prisoner here?
而且 这个俘虏该怎么办
If we don't watch her, she may escape to her fellows.
不看着她 怕是会逃到同伙那边去
That... That's right.
虽…虽然是这样没错
Did the man with long hair go somewhere?
那个长头发的人去哪了么
Why you are worrying about Oni?
为什么你会担心欧尼啊
Say something!
你倒是说话啊
Nibi is also...
尼比也…
Nibi should also be with Oni.
尼比也一定跟欧尼在一起
It sucks...
不公平啊…
Indeed I...
我其实 也不想…
That guy, Nibi,
尼比那家伙
is a lackey of Oni.
就是欧尼的跟屁虫
Shikon, Shikoku...
希孔 希可库
He is so weak.
明明没什么能力
Even if he is with Oni,
就算跟去了
he can definitely only be a passenger.
想必也只能扯他后腿
Where were you guys hiding?
你们躲哪去了
We were not hiding.
我们才不是躲
It's a war decided by the "Muin", right?
这不是那帮无印擅自决定的战争么
Why we should die for them?
凭什么咱们要给他们卖命
We internal moles are not the footmen of Mr. chief.
咱们体内鼹鼠可不是首长大人的佣人
Aren't we?
不是么？
Of course.
当然了
Then why is Oni under the control of Suo?
那为什么欧尼会对苏澳唯命是从
What do you mean?
你想说什么
Oni is risking his life fighting for the useless Muin.
为了什么都做不到的那帮无印的命令
Our leader
咱们的老大
is yielding to the power.
居然会屈从权贵
Don't you think it's weird?
难道你不觉得奇怪么
Nah, Kicha?
是吧 绮茶
I... I think...
我…我啊…
Hey, don't break up!
喂 别搞分裂
Then what about you?
你又算什么
What?
啥？
You are sheltering an enemy.
瞧你还窝藏敌人
Is this an instruction by Suo?
这也是苏澳的指示么
Definitely not!
怎么可能是
Then what?
不是么
Aren't you waggling your tail to the Muin?
难不成是你向那帮无印摇尾巴么
What the hell you are talking!
你丫说啥！
What?
哈？
Want a fight?
想干架么
Oni is!
欧尼他！
Oni is doing what he decided himself!
欧尼他…是自己决定要去的！
Indeed I...!
我其实…！
Indeed I didn't...
我其实 也不想…
want to leave Oni for a single second...
和欧尼分开哪怕一分一秒…
Oni will definitely come back...
欧尼绝对会回来的
Definitely be back with us alive!
绝对 会活着回来的！
Don't waste your time, kill them!
别磨磨唧唧地 给我干掉他们
I will shoot you together next time.
下次连你一起打死
S...Sorry.
对…对不起
What?
真的？
Stop.
慢着
δαίμονας
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
δαίμονας
It seems that this guy is the Daímonas of Fallaina.
听说这家伙是「法莱那的恶灵」
Oni!
欧尼！
So this kid is the berserker made by the Fallaina?
这样的小鬼
Stupid.
真荒唐
It seems that the island of prison has become a fairy land entirely.
看来监狱之岛俨然已经成了童话王国
Last time, the soldiers landed Fallaina for the first time were really surprised.
前阵子 第一次登上法莱那的士兵
φάλαινα
φάλαινα
The sinners of the whale
鲸的罪人们
didn't even know they are the sinners.
都不知道自己是罪人
They have no knowledge about the world outside.
一点外面世界的知识也没有
They didn't know what has happened.
连发生了什么都不知道
It has been a hundred years since the exile.
自流放开始已经过了一百年
The civilization of them is degenerating rather than developing.
文明一点都没发展 反而在退化
They stopped growing because of ignorance, in the fake paradise.
在那虚伪的乐园里 因为无知而停止了成长
I believe you guys don't even know why you are short-lived!
恐怕你们
Sister of Orca,
奥尔卡的妹妹
I can never understand why you were attracted by them.
我是一点也想不通 你到底看上他们什么了
You are the residents of the picture book, which will never be read.
没有人去读的 小人书里的居民
Besides the guilt of your ancestors,
且不算你们祖先的罪过
you are guilty enough,
这就足够罪恶了
with the crime named being meaningless.
没有意义的存在就是罪
I will erase you out.
就让我杀了你们
Your deaths will be the only goodness you can do for the world.
你们的死也算是为了这个世界好
Shut up.
闭嘴
Disappear!
给我消失
You ought to disappear from this world completely,
不要在沙海留下哪怕一粒微尘
The eighth section
第 八 节
You ought to disappear from this world
第 八 节
without even leaving a single sand in the world.
从这世上给我彻底消失
乾いた海の跡　望んで
乾いた海の跡　望んで
Staring into the trace of the dried sea
眺望昔日的大海
まだ見ぬ対岸を描く
まだ見ぬ対岸を描く
I will draw the other side I have never seen
描绘未知的彼岸
囚われの心のままなら
囚われの心のままなら
If you remain your heart in captivity
如果囚禁起心灵  一如过往
こんな傷みも知らずにいた
こんな傷みも知らずにいた
You may live without knowing the pain
又怎会经历如此悲伤
美しい詞を告げたひと
美しい詞を告げたひと
The one who told the beautiful story
是谁讲述起美好的希望
夜明けも待たずに
夜明けも待たずに
Can not wait for the dawn
让我等不及黎明
果てのその先を泳ぐ
果てのその先を泳ぐ
Until beyond the end of world, I am swimming
向着天涯海角扬帆起航
虫の唄
虫の唄
Listen to the insects' song
彻夜虫鸣
眠らず君と聞いた記憶
眠らず君と聞いた記憶
That night is our memory
回忆里与你一起侧耳倾听
手を　ただ結んで
手を　ただ結んで
Just link hand in hand
只是双手相牵
半色でも　遠い国でも
半色でも　遠い国でも
No matter it is twilight or a distant country
不论夕阳  还是远方
短い一章に生まれた夢を
短い一章に生まれた夢を
Born in a short chapter
在这短暂苍渺的一章里
抱きしめに行こう
抱きしめに行こう
But let us go and embrace that dream
一起追逐梦想
The ninth section
第 九 节
I want to watch the future of your choice
因 为 我 想